# James Richards

### **Technical Support Guru**

Las Vegas, NV 89130 richardsjamesw@gmail.com +1 719 888 9122

Online portfolio - https://jwrichards1982.github.io/portfolio/indeed profile - https://my.indeed.com/p/jamesr-kgnaj7h

Top Tier Technical Support rep who's hobbies include almost anything labeled tech and professional experience working as a remote PC support tech for over 8 years. Unique experience handling tech from mid 90's to now.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

### Work Experience

### **Troubleshooting / Help Desk**

Robert Half International - LPL Financial TS/HD - Las Vegas, NV November 2021 to October 2022

Provide remote/in-bound call center, Level 1 Technical Support for customers and Financial Advisors under LPL Financial.

- Reset Active Directory passwords and lockouts
- Setup office 365 Outlook email account
- Resolve and assist in accessing various online tools and websites
- Document calls in a continued effort to resolve common call drivers and develop a work-flow or troubleshooting Knowledge Base

#### **HCL and Barclay's Bank Technical Support**

Yochana IT - Las Vegas, NV October 2021 to November 2021

- · Handle on-boarding of Barclay's employees for work at home equipment assignment
- Helped setup Active Directory accounts and ensure working remote access through VPN
- · Provided support to new and current employees to ensure their access and software works

#### **Migration Support**

Link Technologies, Inc. - Las Vegas, NV July 2021 to August 2021

Short term contract position.

- Setup new Outlook profiles for new company domain
- · Ensured individual computers, laptops and mobile devices moved to the new domain
- Helped identify errors in scripts and issues with processes to refine procedures

#### eero Technical Support (eero.com)

C3 / Everise - Las Vegas, NV September 2020 to June 2021 Technical and Customer support for eero, a WiFi mesh network device manufacturer.

- Responsible for providing in-depth and knowledgeable support for wireless network communication on a mesh network for WiFi connectivity.
- Self training and expanding knowledge on wireless technology
- Customer support when requests for replacement or refunds requested
- Comprehensive and summary training on use of eero and various services offered by eero and its partner companies.

### **Technical Support**

IPGARD - Las Vegas, NV February 2020 to April 2020

Providing internal and external technical support for computer systems and various equipment provided by IPGARD and SmartAVI. Duties include server maintenance, network maintenance, testing and workstation maintenance. Also basic facility maintenance and upkeep. Small sized business where I could be asked to do just about anything.

### **Verizon Premier Support - Tech Coach**

Asurion - Las Vegas, NV June 2019 to February 2020

- Provide support to Verizon Wireless customers and their mobile devices and related equipment
- Integrate and use third-party applications to achieve the customer's goals
- Remote connectivity, Hardware Troubleshooting, Network troubleshooting and third-party equipment integration

### **Technical Support Representative**

DTT / DTiQ - Las Vegas, NV July 2013 to April 2019

- Provide timely support resolution for customers who lease DTT DVR equipment (PC, cameras, switches, routers, etc)
- Handle sensitive documentation and video/audio evidence for Loss Prevention
- Remote connectivity, Hardware Troubleshooting, Network troubleshooting and third party equipment integration

### **Customer Service Assistant**

AT&T - Las Vegas, NV May 2012 to October 2012

Provided technical and Custer support to AT&T ADSL customers in both residential and commercial accounts. Recommended additional services and products when they seemed needed. Helped resolve issues or dispatch service for resolution and followed-up as needed. Directed unresolvable escalations and correctly routed calls to correct department when misdirected.

#### **Customer Support Apple iOS**

ACS, Inc. / Apple - Tualatin, OR October 2009 to July 2011

Provided technical and Custer support to Apple iPhone/iPod/iOS customers. Recommended additional services and products when they seemed needed. Helped resolve issues or directed to service centers for resolution and followed-up as needed. Directed returns and exchanges on failed products in and out

of warranty. Directed unresolvable escalations and correctly routed calls to correct department when misdirected. Also achieved supervisor assistant/team lead in the last three months of employment.

#### Education

### **High School Equivalency in HSE**

Roswell Job Corps - Roswell, NM July 2000 to December 2001

#### Skills

- Windows Xp Windows 10 (6 years)
- Cisco Routers (2 years)
- Network Administration (3 years)
- 3ds Max (1 year)
- C++ (Less than 1 year)
- Java (Less than 1 year)
- Adobe Creative Suite (1 year)
- Microsoft Office (4 years)
- Website Design (1 year)
- HTML5 (1 year)
- CSS3 (1 year)
- Network Support
- Active Directory
- I AN
- · Mobile Devices
- Technical Support
- Help Desk
- VPN
- CRM software (5 years)
- Git
- DNS
- Microsoft Windows Server
- Operating Systems
- English

#### Links

https://jwrichards1982.github.io/portfolio/

#### Certifications and Licenses

### CompTIA A+

September 2014 to September 2017

Lifetime from 2001 till 2014. CE from 2014 to 2017. I can recertify, no problem, if I had the money

### **Microsoft Office User Specialist**

November 2001 to Present

M.O.U.S certified on all the Microsoft Office Suite tools in use and depreciated

#### Assessments

### **Technical Support — Highly Proficient**

November 2019

Performing software, hardware, and network operations.

Full results: Highly Proficient

### **Basic Computer Skills: PC — Expert**

November 2019

Performing basic computer operations, navigating a Windows OS, and troubleshooting common computer problems.

Full results: Expert

### **Forklift Safety — Proficient**

January 2020

Best practices and safety hazards in forklift operation

Full results: Proficient

#### **Customer Focus & Orientation — Highly Proficient**

January 2020

Responding to customer situations with sensitivity

Full results: Highly Proficient

#### **Problem Solving — Expert**

March 2020

Measures a candidate's ability to analyze relevant information when solving problems

Full results: Expert

### **Customer Focus & Orientation — Highly Proficient**

January 2020

Responding to customer situations with sensitivity

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

#### **Call Center Customer Service — Expert**

April 2020

Applying customer service skills in a call center setting.

Full results: Expert

### **Technical Support — Highly Proficient**

April 2020

Performing software, hardware, and network operations.

Full results: Highly Proficient

### Technical support: Customer situations — Proficient

April 2021

Responding to technical support situations with sensitivity

Full results: Proficient

### **Technical support — Highly Proficient**

November 2019

Performing software, hardware, and network operations.

Full results: Highly Proficient

### **Customer service — Highly Proficient**

April 2021

Identifying and resolving common customer issues

Full results: Highly Proficient

### Social media — Completed

April 2021

Creating content, communicating online, and building a brand's reputation.

Full results: Completed

#### Working with MS Excel spreadsheets — Highly Proficient

June 2021

Knowledge of various Microsoft Excel features, functions and formulas

Full results: Highly Proficient

#### **Basic computer skills — Highly Proficient**

June 2021

Performing basic computer operations and troubleshooting common problems

Full results: Highly Proficient

#### Warehouse associate — Proficient

June 2021

Assesses the tendencies that are important for success in warehouse roles

Full results: Proficient

### **Customer service fit — Highly Proficient**

May 2021

Measures the traits that are important for success for customer service roles

Full results: Highly Proficient

### Office manager — Proficient

June 2021

Scheduling and budgeting Full results: <a href="Proficient">Proficient</a>

### Work style: Reliability — Familiar

June 2021

Tendency to be reliable, dependable, and act with integrity at work

Full results: Familiar

### **Manufacturing fit — Familiar**

June 2021

Measures the traits that are important for success in manufacturing roles

Full results: Familiar

### **Typing — Proficient**

June 2021

Transcribing text using a standard keyboard

Full results: Proficient

### **Technical support: Customer situations — Proficient**

April 2021

Responding to technical support situations with sensitivity

Full results: Proficient

## **Technical support — Highly Proficient**

November 2019

Performing software, hardware, and network operations.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.